https://slama.dev/comeback/
https://slama.dev/comeback/
Oh, damn it again.
Ó, to jsem zas čerti.
Gross.
Fuj.
Sorry, Mr. Pacovsky.
Promiňte, pane Pacovský.
What's going on?
Co se děje?
We have a delivery, this.
Máme mandát, tohle.
What is it?
Co to je?
There's a letter inside.
Vevnitř je dopis.
Tomas, if you're reading this letter, it means I'm dead.
Tomáši, jestli čteš tenhle dopis, znamená to, že jsem mrtvá.
Pay my debts and adopt the kids.
Zaplať moje dluhy a adoptuj děti.
If the body is in one piece, coffin, otherwise cremate.
Jestli bude tělo v celku, tak do rakve, jinak spálit.
Thanks, Simona.
Dík, Simona.
Lexa, nothing happened to your mom, it's just a precaution.
Lexo, vaší mamince se přece nic nestalo, to je jen pro případ.
Oh right.
Ajo.
The blue one then.
Tak ten modrý.
Tomas, if you're reading this letter, it means either A, I'm in the hospital, B, at a spa, C, I found someone, D, I've been kidnapped.
Tomáši, jestli čteš tenhle dopis, znamená to, že za A jsem v nemocnici, za B v lázních, za C někoho jsem si našla, za D unesli mě.
Start saving and watch the kids.
Začni šetřit a dohlídni na děti.
If I don't come back within a week, open the red letter.
Když se do týdne nevrátím, otevři červený dopis.
Thanks, Simona.
Dík, Simona.
Nothing else?
Víc nic?
We were also supposed to say, cross out what doesn't apply.
Ještě jsme měli říct, nehodící se škrtněte.
Hey.
Čau.
Hi.
Ahoj.
Simona's disappeared.
Simona zmizela.
I'm going to look for her.
Jdu ji hledat.
Where?
Kam?
No idea.
Nevím.
Probably the hospital or Marianky spa.
Zřejmě do nemocnice nebo do Mariánek.
We think more likely the hospital.
My si myslíme, že spíš do nemocnice.
Because she left on her bike cursing about a stomachache.
Protože odjela na kole a strašně nadávala, že ji bolí břicho.
When she goes to the spa, she usually whistles.
A když jede do lázní, tak si spíš píská.
Which hospital is closest?
Která nemocnice je nejblíž?
The Sisters of No Mercy.
U nemilosrdných sester.
I'll try there.
Tak to zkusím tam.
Wait, that means Simona isn't at the pub?
Moment, ale to znamená, že Simona není v hospodě?
Apparently not.
No zřejmě ne.
But Ozzak has his Saint Patrick's run today.
Ale Ozzák má dneska běh svatýho Patrika.
What on earth is that?
To je zas co, proboha?
Eat a kilo of hot peppers at once and then run to Simona's to wash it down.
Sníst najednou kilo feferonek a pak to běžet k Simoně zapít.
He'll run somewhere else then. The nearest place is Strunc's and that's two kilometers.
Tak poběží jinam. Nejbližší je u Štrunců a to jsou dva kilometry.
That was fast.
To byla fofr.
Yeah, Simona's place is closed.
No, Simona má normálně zavřeno.
Simona disappeared.
Simona zmizela.
Well, alright then.
No tak to jo.
I'm off.
No tak já jdu.
Ivuska, for water, this is actually pretty good.
Ivuško, na to, že to je voda, je to docela dobrý.
It's tap water.
To je voda z vodárny.
Yeah.
Jo.
Buy it more often then.
Tak ji kupuj častějc.
She's the only patient who's ever arrived by bike.
To je jediná pacientka, která k nám přijela na kole.
She had acute appendicitis.
Měla akutní zánět slepého střeva.
Hi, Tomas.
Ahoj, Tomáši.
I'm glad I found you.
No, to jsem rád, že jsem tě našel.
I'll leave you two.
Tak já vás nechám.
But keep an eye on her.
Ale hlídejte mi ji.
The appendix is already out, but after this anesthesia there can be seizures.
Slepák už má venku, ale po téhle anestezii můžou nastat křeče.
But don't worry, it happens very rarely.
A nebojte, nebojte se, stává se to jen velmi zřídka.
Simona, for God's sake, what happened to you?
A Simono, proboha, tak co se ti stalo?
Oh please, I felt sick all morning, like when I was expecting the twins, so I went to the gynecologist just in case.
Ale prosím tě, celý ráno mi bylo blbno, jak když jsem čekala dvojčata, tak jsem si pro jistotu zajela na gyndu.
And thank God, it was just the appendix.
A zaplať pámbu, byl to jenom slepák.
Did you get the letters?
Dopisy jsi dostal?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Jo, jo, jo.
Great.
Super.
And don't forget to always check Sasa's pockets.
A nezapomeň vždycky prohledat Sašu.
She brings bugs home.
Tahá si domů brouky.
What?
Cože?
She keeps wanting a pet.
No, pořád chce nějaký zvířátko.
Lexa wants a daddy, so he brings home homeless people, but those you can't miss.
Lexa zase chce tatínka, tak tahá domů bezdomovce, ale ty nepřehlídneš.
Oh, and tell Ozzak that starting tomorrow Horvat will watch the pub.
Jo, a Ozzákovi vyřiď, že od zítřka ohlídá hospodu Horvát.
Don't worry, we'll manage somehow.
Neboj, my to nějak zvládneme.
How long will you be here?
Dokdy to budeš?
They promised if there are no complications, up to two weeks.
No, slibovali, že když nebudou komplikace, tak i čtrnáct dní.
Let's hope there won't be any.
Tak doufejme, že nebudou.
Don't complain.
Nestěžuj si.
It's like a holiday here.
Vždyť je to tady jak na dovolený.
You just lie around, food brought to your bed, all the tea you want, and all for free.
Člověk se jenom válí, jídlo až do postele, čaje kolik vypiješ a všecko zadarmo.
I wouldn't say free.
No zadarmo bych neřekl.
You know how much you pay those thieving insurance companies?
Víš, co zaplatíš těm zlodějským pojišťovnám?
Oh come on.
Ale.
And Miss Iva, if you need anything, just ring.
A slečno Ivo, kdybyste něco potřebovala, stačí zazvonit.
Thank you.
Děkuju.
What do you mean, Miss Iva?
Jak slečno Ivo?
She must have mistaken me for someone.
Asi si mě s někým spletla.
What?
Cože?
Calm down.
Uklidni se.
How am I supposed to calm down?
Jak se mám uklidnit?
You said yourself those insurance companies are terrible crooks, and Iva's covered by the state.
Sám jsi říkal, že ty pojišťovny jsou strašný zloději, a Ivě to platí stát.
Don't get upset.
No tak se nerozčiluj.
And Sasa isn't covered by the state?
A Saši to neplatí stát?
I registered Sasa as a guide dog.
Sašu jsem nahlásila jako slepeckýho psa.
You get bigger subsidies for a dog than for a child.
Jsou na něj větší příspěvky než na dítě.
You want them to lock me up at the vet?
To bys chtěla, aby mě zavřeli na veterinu?
Are you making fun of the state?
To si z toho stát děláš srandu?
I figured you wouldn't understand.
No já jsem si myslela, že to nepochopíš.
I certainly don't.
No to teda nepochopím.
And brace yourself for the burger.
A těš se na ten buger.
Stop faking.
Nesimuluj.
Everyone get out.
Všichni jděte pryč.
That fraud is faking it.
Ta podvodnice simuluje.
Out!
Ven!
Dad, I can handle it.
Víš, tati, já to zvládnu.
I'll call the doctor.
Víš, zavolám doktora.
There, it's passed.
Tak, a je to pryč.
What are you doing here?
No co tady děláš?
I sleep here.
Spím tady.
Hold on.
No moment.
Come back, I'll catch them.
Pojď zpátky, já je pochytám.
Yeah right, the apartment is full of them.
Jo, to bych chtěl vidět, jich je plný byt.
What's going on?
Co se děje?
My bed bugs escaped.
Utekly mi ploštice.
Let them be.
Nech se plnit.
No way, one crawled into my ear.
Nejdu, jedna mi vlezla do ucha.
What?
Cože?
I just wanted a pet until Mom comes back.
Když já jsem jenom chtěla mít zvířátko, než se maminka vrátí.
And I got a few extras just in case.
A vzala jsem jich pro jistotu víc.
Idiot, I brought you a spider.
Krávo, když jsem ti přines pavouka.
Ew, a spider.
Fuj, pavouk.
What's going on here?
Co se to tady děje?
Nothing, they can't fall asleep.
Nic, nemůžou usnout.
Did you find Mom?
Našel jste maminku?
Yes, she's in the hospital, but she'll be fine.
Ne, je v nemocnici, ale bude v pořádku.
It was the appendix.
Byl to slepák.
You went to the eye doctor for it?
Vy jste za ním byli na očním?
The appendix is a body part, Lexa.
Slepák je střevo, Lexo.
Shut up, you goose.
Sklapni, huso.
Don't call her names.
Nenadávej jí.
She just said I'm a body part.
Vždyť řekla, že jsem střevo.
She said the appendix is a body part, Lexa.
Řekla, že slepák je střevo, Lexo.
You too?
Ty taky?
Enough.
Tak dost.
From now on you two listen to me.
Od teďka vy dva posloucháte mě.
So, home and sleep.
Takže domů a spát.
You too. In the morning we'll sit down and figure out what's next.
Vy taky, ráno si sednem, řekneme co dál.
Can you handle it?
Ty to zvládneš?
I can handle even bed bugs.
Tak to zvládnu i ploštice.
But Mr. Pacovsky, tomorrow there's no breakfast.
Ale, pane Pacovský, zítra snídaně není.
Tomorrow is a weekday.
Zítra je všední den.
As an exception then.
Tak výjimečně.
Awesome.
Super.
Good night.
Dobrou.
Well, good night.
Tak dobrou noc.
Good?
Dobrou?
Ozzak has a kilo of hot peppers in his belly, he's dreaming he's on fire.
Ozzák má v břiše kilo feferonek, zdá se mu, že hoří.
He screams in his sleep?
Křičí ze spaní?
No, he puts out fires in his sleep.
Ne, hasí ze spaní.
Good morning.
Dobré ráno.
Morning.
Dobré.
Oh, you're already here.
A, vy už jste tady.
Since five.
Už od pěti.
What, they woke you up?
Co, oni tě vzbudili?
No.
Ne.
Ozzak finished putting out fires at four thirty.
Ozzák dohasil v půl pátý.
But when we came, the shirt was just smoldering.
Ale když jsme přišli, ta košile jenom doutlala.
So why were you here so early?
No a proč jste tu byli tak brzo?
Because we didn't know you don't eat breakfast until you wake up.
Když bychom nevěděli, že snídáte, až když se probudíte.
When do you normally eat breakfast?
A kdy vy snídáte?
When Mom comes home from work, we have breakfast together, she goes to sleep, and then our daily program starts.
No, když máma přijde z práce, společně se nasnídáme, ona jde spát a nám začíná denní program.
Usually we wait until dawn so we can see to string the beads.
Většinou ale čekáme, než se rozední, abychom na to navlíkání korálků viděli.
Electricity isn't free.
Elektřina není zadarmo.
Bon appetit.
Tak dobrou chuť.
Ow, what kind of tea is this?
Au, co to máte za čaj?
It's hot.
Bývá horkej.
Not the tea.
Čaj ne.
It's kind of dirty.
To je nějakej špinavej.
What's that brown tea called?
Jak se jmenuje ten hnědej čaj?
Black, that's black tea.
Černej, to je černej čaj.
Oh.
Aha.
Could I get the cold clear kind that Mom gives us?
Nemoh bych dostat takovej ten studenej a průhlednej, co nám dává máma?
Stop it, blow on it and eat.
Přestaňte, ty si to vyfoukej a jezte.
For next time.
Pro příště.
At our place, breakfast is at seven thirty, dinner is between six and seven.
U nás se snídá až v půl osmý, večeře je mezi šestou a sedmou.
When do you normally go to bed?
Kdy normálně chodíte spát?
When it gets dark, because you can't see the beads anymore.
Když se setmí, to už zas není vidět na korálky.
But we can still watch the moon before bed.
Ale ještě se přece před spáním můžeme dívat na měsíc.
Yeah, but you got the moon banned for 14 days for that chemistry ball thing.
Jo, ale ty máš za tu kouli s chemií teďka měsíc na 14 dní zakázaný.
It's waning anyway.
Stejně teď couvá.
So here's the deal, bedtime is 10 PM, and if you want, you can watch TV at our place before that.
Takže jinak, spát budete chodit v 10 večer, když budete chtít, můžete se předtím u nás dívat na televizi.
Oh wow, sis!
Ty jo, ségra!
But I've just gotten into watching the moon.
Když já mám teďka rozkoukanej ten měsíc.
What did I do to deserve this?
Co jsem komu udělal, co?
Why are you crying?
Proč brečíš?
For God's sake, Simona didn't give the blue envelope to your dad.
Proboha, Simona nedala tu modrou obálku vašemu tátovi.
Or grandma.
Nebo babičce.
He already paints at grandma's a lot.
Když on už se u babičky dost často maluje.
And Dad, whenever he could watch us, he's on a polar expedition.
No a táta, vždycky když by nás mohl hlídat, tak je na polární expedici.
Tough luck, right?
Smůla, že jo?
Sorry I'm late.
Pardon, že jdu pozdě.
I went to the health insurance office to ask how much you can get for insurance fraud.
Byl jsem se zeptat na zdravotní pojišťovně, kolik člověk může dostat za pojišťovací podvod.
More than for murder?
Víc než za vraždu?
Why do you ask?
Proč vás to zajímá?
Because Simona is in the hospital with appendicitis under someone else's ID number.
Protože Simona leží v nemocnici se slepákem na cizí rodný číslo.
Oh my.
No teda.
Although...
I když...
Actually, in her situation it makes sense.
Vlastně v její situaci to dává smysl.
And what about my situation, doesn't that matter?
No a co moje situace, ta vás nezajímá?
Iva is covered by the state after all.
Tak za Ivu to přece platí stát.
Fine, but it's still fraud.
No dobře, ale stejně je to podvod.
Shouldn't I report it?
Neměl bych to nahlásit?
The insurance company even has a bonus program for that.
Pojišťovna na to už dokonce vyhlásila bonusprogram.
A bonus program, surely.
Snad bonusprogram.
Yes, a bonus program.
Ne, bonusprogram.
For every report you get a multivitamin and some chips.
Za každé udání dostanete multivitamin a křupky.
But Simona is your friend.
Ale Simona je přece vaše kamarádka.
She's just used to getting away with everything.
Ona je prostě zvyklá, že jí vždycky všechno projde.
But I'm not helping her with this.
Ale já jí v tom pomáhat nebudu.
And who pushed her in a wheelchair to social services when she applied for disability?
A kdo ji odtlačil na vozíku na sociálku, když si šla žádat o invalidní důchod?
She told me she had a sprained ankle.
No tak namluvila mi, že má vyvrtnutý kotník.
And who got her a Castle Guard uniform when she wanted a half-price tram pass?
A kdo jí sehnal uniformu hradní stráže, když chtěla tramvajenku za polovic?
Fine, I stupidly fell for the story that she was going to a costume party.
Dobře, blbě jsem si skočil na to, že jde na maškarní.
But that's over now.
Ale s tím je konec.
Tomas, you're doing this for yourself too.
Tomáši, děláte to přece i pro sebe.
How for myself?
Jak pro sebe?
What if they found out and locked Simona up?
Kdyby na to přišli a Simonu zavřeli?
What about the kids?
Co děti?
Right.
Jasně.
They'd bring me the red letter.
Přinesli by mi červený dopis.
Exactly.
Přesně.
Irma, the guests are coming.
Irma, hosté jdou.
Welcome, your honor.
Pěkně vítám, pán veľkomožný.
Howdy.
Nazdar.
You've got someone here?
Ty tady někoho máš?
No, that's marketing.
Ne, to je marketing.
Who?
Kdo?
A little trick so it doesn't look like an abandoned bar.
No, taký figeľ, aby to tu nevyzeralo ako v opustenej krčme.
What'll you have?
Co to bude?
A beer, but it should've been here already.
No pivo, ale už tady mělo bejt.
Radanka, the guests are complaining.
Radanka, hostia sa sťažujú.
Excuse me, one moment.
Prepáčte, momentíček.
Wait, wait, wait, she always marks it down only when she brings me the beer.
Počkej, počkej, počkej, si, ona mi vždycky dělá čárku, až když mi nese pivo.
That's so we don't forget.
To je ale, abysme nezabudli.
Right, it's pouring and here it is.
Tak, už se to točí a už to tu je.
There you go.
Nech sa páči.
It's not a full pint.
Vždyť nemá míru.
It's a Slovak pint, it's smaller.
To je slovenský politér, má méně.
Why?
A proč?
Smaller country, smaller pint.
Menší štát, menší politér.
I see.
Aha.
You're making another tally mark?
Už si zase děláš čárku?
Well, you told me to yourself.
No, vždyť jsi mi to sám pověděl.
Oh, right.
Aha, ano.
Cheers.
Tak na zdraví.
Cheers to you too.
Aj na tvoje.
Damn it, I said six thirty, didn't I?
Tak sakra, řekl jsem v půl sedmý, ne?
I'll go get him.
Tak já pro něj skočím, no.
Good evening.
Dobrý večer.
So where are you?
Tak kde jste?
We're waiting for you with dinner.
Čekáme na vás s večeří.
Great, there's dinner, even though it's usually every other day.
Super, bude večeře, i když bývá ob den.
Sorry, Mr. Pacovsky, we'd rather save tonight's dinner for tomorrow so we don't go hungry at the end of the week.
Promiňte, pane Pacovský, my bychom si tu večeři radši nechali na zítra, abychom neměli na konci týdne hlad.
What do you mean, hungry.
Jak hlad.
Well, for a week we get three breakfasts and three dinners, so we shouldn't use them all now.
No, na týden jsou přece tři snídaně a tři večeře, tak abysme si to všechno nevybrali teď.
What do you mean three breakfasts, three dinners?
Jak tři snídaně, jak tři večeře?
What about lunch?
A co oběd?
That's on Sundays.
Ten je v neděli.
Good Lord.
Ježíšmaria.
Stop that and come eat.
Nechte toho a pojďte jíst.
Lexa, quit fooling around and come.
Tak Lexo, neblbni a pojď.
I'll smack you on Friday for this.
Ten pátek tě tak přeplácnu.
And Saturday there's a sausage tasting at Harenda.
A v sobotu je v Harendu ochutnávka klobás.
Good evening.
Dobrý večer, prajem.
Here we are. What are you doing here so early?
Tak jsme tu. Co tady děláš tak brzo?
Bro, Simona is Simona, but Horvat...
Brácha, Simona je Simona, ale Horvát...
That guy really knows how to run a place.
Ten sa dokáže, už tam gazda, postarat.
Imagine, he pours so fast that you drink 40 beers in the time you'd normally do 20, and he even walks you home.
Představ si, točí tak rychle, že člověk dá 40 kousků za dobu, kdy normálně udělá tak 20, a ještě tě odvede domů.
You drank 40 beers?
Ty jsi vypil 40 piv?
Yeah, and I'm not even wasted.
No, a ani říznout jsem se nenechal.
Really.
Ozaj.
So with your dad, is there some limit?
Tak s tátou máš nějaký limit, ne?
What limit?
Na čo limit?
When he's thirsty, let him drink.
Keď má slinu, tak nechaj ho.
He's a bartender, right?
To je výčepák, co?
A gem.
Jedna báseň.
But I have a deal with Simona that the limit is 15.
Ale já mám se Simonou dohodu, že limit je 15.
Right.
No veď.
That comes to just...
Robí to iba...
14,150.
14 150.
15 beers, for God's sake, not fourteen hundred.
15 piv, proboha, ne čtrnáct stovek.
That's what you say.
To vravíte vy.
I gave you a discount.
Dal jsem vám zľavu.
Beer for 35 crowns?
Pivo za 35 korun?
Where's the discount?
A kde je ta zľava?
Every fiftieth one is free.
Do každej päťdesiatej má zadarmo.
But he only drank forty.
Ale vždyť jich vypil jenom čtyřicet.
Tomorrow he'll have to try harder.
Zajtra sa bude musieť viacej snažiť.
Sure, bro, relax, I can do it.
Jasně, brácha, klid, já to zvládnu.
But just in case, I'll have a few more hot peppers.
Ale pro jistotu si dám znovu pár feferonek.
Bon appetit.
Dobrou chuť.
Simona, we need to talk.
Simono, musíme si promluvit.
What?
Co?
Is that how you look?
To vypadáš?
Just in case.
Pro jistotu.
So they believe I'm sixteen.
Aby mi věřili, že je mi šestnáct.
You look like a clown.
Vypadáš jako maškara.
Jesus, you're so behind the times, this is what people wear now.
Ježíš, ty jsi sexist, to se teďka nosí.
Give me a break.
No dovol.
I'm acting, in case someone walks by.
Hraju, kdyby šel někdo kolem.
God, what if they see through you?
Ježišmarja, co když tě prokouknou?
Relax.
V klidu.
I got stuffed animals, I cry a lot, I always have my phone, and I don't eat rolls so I don't get fat.
Sehnala jsem si plyšáky, hodně brečím, furt mám v ruce mobil a nejím housky, abych nebyla tlustá.
And I'm also learning the right words.
A taky se učím správný slova.
Here, ask me how school was.
Hele, zeptej se mě, jak bylo ve škole.
How was school?
Jak bylo ve škole?
Lit!
Cajk!
Thank God Iva doesn't talk like that.
Zaplať pánbůh, že Iva takhle nemluví.
Good thing I'm here, they'd never believe it from her.
Tak ještě, že jsem tady já, jí by to už vůbec nevěřili.
What do you want?
Co chceš?
You should talk to Horvat.
Měla bys promluvit s Horvátem.
I'm not speaking to Horvat.
S Horvátem se nebavím.
He's not keeping the limit.
Nedrží limit.
Ozzak cost me just today what he normally does in a week.
Ozzák mě jenom za dnešek stál, co za týden.
So you'll talk to him?
Tak promluvíš s ním?
Lit.
Cajk.
Even though I don't know what that means.
I když já nevím, co to znamená.
You're a fossil.
Ty jsi fosil.
Like, yeah?
Jakože jo, ne?
Just say it normally.
Říkej mi to normálně.
Fine.
No tak jo.
I'll talk to him.
Já to s ním proberu.
He's supposed to stop by anyway.
Stejně se tu má stavit.
Thanks.
Dík.
Are you the father?
Vy jste otec?
Yes, Pacovsky.
Ano, Pacovský.
Then tell your daughter to return those toys to pediatric oncology.
Tak řekněte své dceři, ať ty hračky na tu dětskou onkologii kouká vrátit.
Well, Iva...
No, Ivo...
Iva!
Ivo!
What?
Co?
Sis, sis, look, they're replaying that ad about the laundry detergent that works better than the other one.
Ségra, ségra, čum na to, zas opakujou ten film o tom pracím prášku, co vypadá líp než ten denní.
Don't bother me, I'm growing.
Neruš, dorůstám.
Are there still bed bugs at your place?
Jsou u vás doma ještě ty ploštice?
Just Zanetka and Ivanka.
Už jenom Žanetka s Ivankou.
Virka and Johanka went off somewhere.
Vírka a Johanka někam odešly.
You gave them names?
Ty jsi jim dala jména?
Everyone names their pet.
Každej si svý zvířátko pojmenuje.
How else would I call them?
Jak bych na ně jinak volala?
How do you call bed bugs?
Jak voláš na ploštice?
Well.
No.
Zanetka, Ivanka.
Žanetko, Ivanko.
Like that?
A tak?
And do they actually come?
A ony jako přijdou?
No.
To ne.
Want to go see them?
Chceš se na ně jít podívat?
Then why did you ask about them?
Ne.
I wanted to hide from Lexa at your place.
Chtěla jsem se k vám schovat před Lexou.
But if Zanetka and Ivanka are still there, I'll stay here for a bit.
Ale jestli je tam pořád Žanetka a Ivanka, tak trochu zůstanu tady.
Hey, they're showing something with instant soup.
Ty jo, teď tam dávaj něco s polívkou v pytlíku.
That's definitely about astronauts.
To bude určitě o kosmonautech.
About time you showed up.
No to je dost, že jsi tady.
Lit.
Cajk.
Dad.
Tati.
What, don't you young people talk like this?
No co, vy mladí takhle nemluvíte?
Yeah, but you don't talk like that.
Jo, ale ty takhle nemluv.
I'm a fossil after all.
Jsem přeci fosil.
You didn't hear me.
Ty jsi mě asi neslyšel.
Don't talk like that.
Ty takhle nemluv.
Okay, okay.
No, no.
Did you talk to Mom?
Mluvili jste s maminkou?
Yeah.
Jo.
Is she feeling better?
A už je jí líp?
She's totally rejuvenated there.
Úplně tam omládla.
Lit.
Cajk.
Hello, could you please connect me to surgery?
Dobrý den, můžete mě prosím vás spojit na chirurgii?
Thank you.
Děkuji.
Hello.
No.
Yo, it's Tom.
Čus, tady Tom.
I'm calling about Iva Pacovska.
Volám kvůli Ivě Pacovský.
Yeah, we go to the same school.
No, chodíme spolu do stejné školy.
Tomas, what are you doing?
Tomáši, co to děláte?
One sec.
Momentík.
I'm calling the hospital asking about Simona as her teenage friend, so they believe she's 16.
Volám do nemocnice a ptám se na Simonu jako její teenagerský kamarád, aby věřili, že jí je 16.
Give it here, anyone can tell you're a total fossil.
Dejte to sem, vás každý pozná, že jste úplnej fosil.
How do you know their slang?
Jak to, že znáte ty jejich slova?
I ride the tram sometimes, check it.
Občas jezdím tramvají, čekujte.
Yo, this is Maca, I wanna ask.
Čus, tady Máca, si chci zeptat.
How much longer is Iva gonna be at your place?
Jak dlouho ještě bude u vás Iva ležet?
Don't give me grief, her old man will give me the number.
No nemusíte mi hned dávat čočku, její fotr mi dá číslo.
Today, yeah?
Dneska, jo?
Wicked gnarly.
Mrťa krušný.
Sweet, I'll give her fossil the heads-up.
Sjela buřtguláš, že tomu jejímu fosilovi dám echo.
Peace out.
Tak zdarec.
Well, Marcelka.
No, Marcelko.
I was brutally strict, wasn't I?
Byla jsem krutopřísná, že?
Yes you were.
To ano.
Now they won't suspect her, and she's going home right after rounds anyway.
Teď už ji podezřívat nebudou a stejně jde hned po vizitě domů.
I'm off then.
Tak já jedu.
You'll manage here alone.
Víte, tady sama zvládnete.
Sure.
Jasně.
Lit.
Cajk.
Hurry up!
Tak dělej!
The instructions from Simona are written in pencil on a napkin.
Ty instrukce od Simony sú napísané tužkou na obrúsku.
You can't read them.
To sa nedá prečítať.
Pour beer when he's on the steps.
Točit pivo, keď je na schodoch.
And what would beer be doing on the steps?
A čo by robilo pivo na schodoch?
When I'm on the steps.
Když já jsem na schodech.
Me?
Já?
So go to the steps.
No, tak choď na ty schody.
There, hop to it and pour.
A je to, přeskoč a toč.
And today I want a Czech measure.
A dneska chci českou míru.
Sure thing.
Ať hej.
I have that written down too.
To mám tiež napísané.
That's what it should look like.
Tak to má vypadat.
Why are you so grumpy?
Co jsi takovej otrávenej?
Because I'm bored!
Keď mě to nebaví!
Doing everything exactly as it's written.
Robiť všetko, ako je to napísané.
Anything creative is forbidden.
Všetko kreatívne mám zakázané.
Making extra tally marks, pouring under measure, watering down the beer.
Robiť čiarky navyše, točiť pod mieru, riediť pivo vodou.
That's like slave labor!
To už vyzerá ako robota!
I actually understand you.
Já tě vlastně rozumím.
With a donkey like you, you could really get things done.
S takým somárom, ako si ty, by sa dokázali veci.
But all I'm allowed to do is make tally marks until there are 15.
Ale všetko, čo mám povolené, je robiť čiarky, pokiaľ jich nebude 15.
You know what, just write fifteen right away and let's start drinking.
No víš co, když tam napíš rovnou patnáct a začnem chlastat.
Maybe, you're not such a donkey after all.
Možno, nie si taky somár?
They had breakfast too.
No snídani měli taky.
What do you mean?
Jak jako?
Breakfast and dinner in the same day?
Snídani i večeři v jeden den?
So you've spoiled them.
Takže jsi mi je rozmazlil.
Look Simona, I don't want to discuss your parenting.
Hele, Simono, o tý tvojí výchově nechci mluvit.
But I don't think staying with us hurt them.
Ale nemyslím si, že by jim to u nás nějak ublížilo.
Quite the opposite.
Spíš naopak.
Yesterday for example, Sasa learned to shower with the lights on.
Včera se třeba Saša naučila sprchovat při rozsvíceném světle.
Are you crazy?
Blázníš?
Is electricity free?
Copak je elektrika zadarmo?
Plus, yesterday it was Lexa's turn to shower.
A navíc včera se měl sprchovat Lexa.
He took a bath.
No ten si dal vanu.
What?
Cože?
I step out for a moment and you turn my kids into Rockefellers.
Tak já se na chvilku odskočím a ty mi z dětí děláš Rockefellery.
Come on.
No dovol.
Come on what?
No jaký dovol?
You might as well have given them an allowance.
No to jsi jim třeba mohl dát rovnou kapesný.
I did.
No dal.
But only two hundred.
Ale jenom dvě stovky.
They spent two hundred crowns?
Tak oni utratili dvěstě korun?
No, definitely not.
Ne, to určitě ne.
Sasa immediately put the two-hundred note in a frame, and the super saw Lexa burying something in the garden.
Saša si tu dvoustovku hned dala do rámečku a Lexu viděla správcová něco zahrabávat na zahradě.
Wait till you're the one in the hospital.
Tak počkej, až půjdeš do nemocnice ty.
You think I'd leave Iva in your care?
A ty si jako myslíš, že bych dal Ivu tobě na starost?
Who else then?
Jo, a komu?
Ozzak?
Ozzákovi?
Wait, I'll get you back for this.
Počkej, to ti vrátím.
How?
A jak jako?
I'll let Iva have a party at your place.
Povolím Ivě u vás do Mejdán.
With bowling pins.
S kůlkami.
And alcohol.
A alkoholem.
Hard liquor.
Tvrdým.
Horvat?
Horvát?
Simona!
Simona!
You're back already?
Ty už jsi zpět?
As you can see.
Jak vidíš.
Have a beer, tonight it's on Horvat.
Pojď si dát pivo, dneska je to na Horváta.
Horvat?
Horvát?
15 tally marks.
15 čárek.
30 beers short.
Chybí 30 piv.
We had this promotion to bring in customers.
Máme takovou akci, abysme ti přitáhli zákazníky.
I can see business is booming.
No, tak to vidím, že se ti daří.
They'll bring me customers.
No, mě přitáhneš.
You drank them?
To si vypiješ?
We already drank them.
No, už jsme to vypili.
You're paying for that keg.
Ten sud zaplatíš.
No, Simona, it's marketing.
Ne, Simona, to je marketing.
If you don't bring money by tomorrow, I'll show you marketing.
Jestli do zítřka nepřineseš prachy, tak ti ukážu marketing.
And get out!
A ven!
Can you believe this?
No toto?
So...
Tak...
Simona, I'm taking care of the pub for you while you're lounging around hospitals.
Simona, ja sa ti tu starám, o krčmu, zatiaľ čo ty si vyhrívaš po špitáloch.
I could break my arms and legs and this is what I get?
Ruky, nohy si môžem dolámat a toto mám za to?
Bye.
Servus.
Hello.
Zdravím.
Bro.
Brácha.
How's it going?
Jak to vypadá?
It's four in the afternoon.
Jsou čtyři odpoledne.
Yeah, and we've got this promotion going.
Jo, a máme jakou akci.
You'll have a promotion tomorrow at the store.
Budeš mít akci zítra v obchodě.
I make fifteen tally marks and slack off the rest of the time?
Udělám patnáct čárek a budu se jeden chvíli starat?
No.
Ne.
Marcelka will mark a tally for every crate you unload.
Marcelka ti udělá čárku za každou bednu, kterou vybalíš.
And there are at least thirty.
A jejich tam nejméně třicet.
Ooh, even more.
Uuu, více.
Mommy!
Maminko!
Mom!
Mami!
Hey, hey, hey.
No, no, no.
We bought this for you from our allowance.
Tohle jsme ti koupili z kapesného.
Nice flowers.
Hezká kytka.
Thanks.
Díky.
Do you have the receipt?
Máte účet?
Yes, we do.
Ano, máme.
Good.
Fajn.
Mom, guess what, at the Pacovskys' they eat every day.
Mami, představ si, že u Pacovských jedí každý den.
And in the bathroom they can even turn the red faucet.
A v koupelně můžou otáčet i červeným kohoutkem.
Like this.
Takhle.
The Pacovskys are a peculiar family.
Pacovský jsou taková zvláštní rodina.
But at our place, like everywhere else, there are breakfast days and dinner days, and the red faucet releases gas.
Ale u nás, stejně jako u všech ostatních, jsou snídaňový a večeřový dny, pod červeným kohoutkem se pouští plyn.
You don't want to blow up, do you?
No chcete snad vybuchnout?
No.
To ne.
But their water was so nicely warm.
Když ta jejich voda byla taková příjemně teplá.
Warm water gives you pneumonia.
Z teplý vody je zápal plic.
You sure forgot fast how good we have it together.
No, to jste rychle zapomněli na to, jak je nám spolu dobře.
We haven't forgotten, Mom.
Nezapomněli, maminko.
We're happiest with you.
S tebou je nám nejlíp.
You're trying awfully hard.
Ty se nějak snažíš.
Some bugs must have escaped again, huh?
To by zas utekly nějaký brouci, co?
I caught them all already, only Zanetka was left and I'll catch her too.
Už jsem je všechny pochytala, už byla jenom Žanetka a tu taky chytím.
Alright.
Tak dobře.
And you, Lexa?
A ty, Lexo?
No homeless people?
Žádný bezdomovci?
No, Mom.
Ne, mami.
Yeah right, you wanted to bring one home.
Jo, jo, jednoho jsi chtěl vzít.
But I didn't.
No, ale nevzal.
He smelled too bad.
Moc smrděl.
Good, Lexa.
Dobře, Lexo.
You don't still have the moon ban, do you?
Nemáš náhodou ještě zakázaný ten měsíc?
Yeah, ten more days.
No jo, ještě deset dnů.
I'm lifting it.
Tak to ruším.
You can look at it.
Můžeš se koukat.
Awesome, it's already growing back.
Super, už začal dorůstat.
I don't think the moon grows, it's not a plant.
Myslím, že nemůže měsíc dorůstat, když to není kytka.
Oh right.
Ajo.
Dad.
Tati.
Yeah?
No?
If you ever have to go to the hospital, send me to an orphanage instead.
Kdybys někdy musel do nemocnice, pošli mě radši do děcáku.
You can count on it.
Spolehni se.
You thought I wouldn't find you, huh?
Myslel jsi, že tě nenajdu, co?